n Dierbouh

Résidence Gaia Frange Maritime, Oran, Algeria

□+213551081911/+31629153326 | ≥ cv@dsalim.dev | ☆ dsalim.dev | □ CaddyDz | ≧ salim-djerbouh | □

CaddyDz | ¥ saly3301



Jan. 2023 - Present

Oct. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Oct. 2022 - Dec. 2023

Summary

Software engineer, full-stack web developer, and DevOps/SysAdmin. Extensive experience in developing and maintaining high-traffic, dataintensive, and feature-rich web-facing applications and APIs. Over seven years of experience specializing in back-end development, infrastructure engineering, and CI/CD pipelines automation. Super nerd with a critical mindset, who loves Vim, macOS, and Linux, enjoys setting up and customizing development environments. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools when the need arises.

Skills_

Pure functional, object oriented in PHP, Javascript ES6, C#, Python, Shell Scripting, bits of Golang and Ruby. **Programming**

Engineering Systems architecture, optimizing performance, data transformations, access control & security, testing, Modular design...

Languages English, Arabic, French and Dutch.

Front-end Designing interfaces, screens responsiveness, state management, reactivity, animation, accessibility, bundling, tree shaking...

Back-end Databases like Postgres, caching, routing, validation, authentication, billing, creating and consuming REST APIs...

DevOps Deployment, version control, server administration and maintenance, networking, containers, virtualization, error reporting...

Tools Jira, Confluence, Obsidian, Git, Swagger and Postman.

Work Experience _____

DiDCentral, LLC Remote

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER July. 2023 - Present

- Built a queue based system to transcribe VoIP calls and catch fraudulent ones via a machine learning model.
- Created a CRM for managing customers and their invoices.
- Built the RoboGuard product which blocks bad actors from ISP networks.
- Created a system to trap future calls in honeypots to process by the system.
- Creating a mission control system analytics dashboard for customers network insights and for AU/US government regulation compliance.

Le Four Numérique Remote

FRONT-END DEVELOPER July. 2023 - October. 2023

- Implemented design wireframes as an interactive web application.
- Created a progressive web application for automobile insurance companies.
- Handled complex industrial user interfaces for workshops.

Upwork Remote

• Built a full-stack web-app for a financial management platform.

- Built a multi-tenancy modular architecture SaaS product.
- Built a full-stack webapp for a travel agency with Laravel and Vue.
- Fixing and/or improving deployment setups for various apps.

OrderSpark Remote, USA (Freelance)

BACKEND DEVELOPER, DEVOPS LEAD

FREELANCE FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- · Built management portal UI and backend (Laravel Nova).
- · Built marketing site API.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- Handled all DevOps infrastructure and software architecture.
- Organized, secured, cleaned up and documented system resources thereby reducing operating costs.

One Potato, Ltd Remote, USA (Freelance)

- Setup a staging server/environment eliminating bugs in acceptance phase.
- Redesigned the deliveries page significantly improving the user experience.
- · Fixed frontend edge cases bugs.
- Refactored and cleaned up parts of the codebase to enhance maintainability.
- Developed a weekly total billing component.

Jan. 2022 - May. 2022

BACKEND ENGINEER, DEVOPS

- Debugging and maintaining a Django framework based admin panel.
- Connecting uploaded audio file briefs to AWS S3 with Amazon Alexa.
- Maintaining deployments on Heroku.
- · Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.

Shyfter, SRL. Brussels, Belgium (Remote)

BACKEND ENGINEER, DEVOPS ASSIST

Feb. 2021 - Aug 2022

June. 2021 - December 2021

March. 2019 - April. 2020

- Integrated government services with compliance to security requirements like Dimona and audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- Switched deployment infrastructure improving runtime performance by 34% and reducing costs by almost 900%.
- Worked on customer exclusive features and requirements.
- Built Redis based queue system and moved long processing operations to background jobs.
- · Migrated legacy codebase from pure procedural PHP to resusable service classes resulting maintainability.
- Refactored code base reducing algorithmic complexity and also enforced coding standards for consistency.
- Built a printable dynamic GATT documents and assisted frontend team on API consumption.

Salesforce, Inc San Francisco, California (Remote)

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- Wrote the full test-suite for Unit, Feature and Browser QA tests.
 Developed and maintained CI/CD pipeline on GitHub with actions and Heroku deployments as well as review apps on branches connecting everything to Jira development board.
- · Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- · Eliminated bottle-neck performance issues.
- Created bulk CSV import for customer invitations thereby improving leads generation.
- Improved UX by building a campaign flow saver.
- · Added a way for managers to flag users as (free access) so they don't get charged via Stripe.
- Automated fixing Salesforce branding via GitHub actions.

Didata LLC. Zürich, Switzerland

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Wrote example testing data seeders for BioLab research application.
- Implemented an ACL architecture for Backend API.
- · Wrote mutations mapping module for state management following the Flux pattern for the Frontend application.
- Implemented several CRUD models.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2016-2024 Top %4, Overall Stack Overflow members.

International

2018-2020 Top #37, PHP ranking GitHub awards.

Amsterdam,

Netherlands

Presentation

GDG Conference Blida, Algeria

Presenter for < Machine Learning Theory>

Nov. 2017

- · Introduced the theory of machine learning genetic algorithms with an analogy of evolutionary biology.
- Introduced how machine learning algorithms work with an implementation of an SAT resolver in symbolic regression.

OpenMinds Linux install party

Algiers, Algeria

SPEAKER < A LOOK INTO THE KERNEL INTERNALS>

Apr. 2017

A brief talk about the Linux kernel source tree and subsystems with a short introduction to OSDev.

Education

Lounici Ali University
Final Year English Literature

Blida, Algeria

Sep. 2013 - Jan. 2016

- American history, civilization & literature.
- Studied English linguistics and works of Noam Chomsky.